Eastern New York, Association of College and Research Libraries (ENY/ACRL) Chapter; Records mss153
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Eastern New York, Association of College and Research Libraries (ENY/ACRL) Chapter Records
1975-2024
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
mss153
73.8 MB
.17 cubic ft.
This collection contains materials related to the organizational activities of the Eastern New York, Association of College and Research Libraries (ENY/ACRL) Chapter.
Content Description
The collection predominantly contains digital files transfered from ENY-ACRL's web site in 2024 including organizational documents such as bylaws, organizational handbooks, and awards, as well as meeting minutes from the organization and Board of Directors, newsletters, conference programs, and annual reports to ACRL. There are also a small amount of paper records.
Biographical / Historical
The Eastern New York, Association of College and Research Libraries (ENY/ACRL) is the local chapter of the national Association of College and Research Libraries and promotes professional standards, mentors librarians, and enhances professional development through a variety of educational programs. ACRL is dedicated to improving library services, encouraging the exchange of ideas and information, providing networking opportunities for librarians and seeking greater cooperation among academic and research libraries. The organization hosts annual meetings and webinar trainings.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Then ENY/ACRL archivist (and M.E. Grenander archivist) Jodi Boyle took files directly from the ENY/ACRL website in 2024. A small number of additional records were donated directly from David Schuster (current program chair) and Christina Swendsrud (former secretary) to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives in 2024. Emily Mock, Treasurer of ENY/ACRL, also donated materials located from previous officers in 2024.
Arrangement of the Collection
The materials are arranged in seven series; series 1 is arranged alphabetically while series 2-7 are arranged chronologically.
Association of College and Research Libraries. Eastern New York Chapter; Administrative reports; Annual reports; Newsletters; Conference reports; Business and Industry
- Administration, 1994-2018; 3.22 MB
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  The Administrative series contains organizational materials such as bylaws, officer's handbooks, past chapter officers, member institutions, and award documetnation.
  - ENY/ACRL Board Handbook, 2018 August 1
  - ENY/ACRL By-Laws, 2013 May
  - ENY/ACRL Library Innovation Award, 2011-2015
  - ENY/ACRL Officer's Handbook, Revised Edition, 1998; 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ENY/ACRL Officer's Handbook, Suggested Revisions, 2000; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ENY/ACRL Past Chapter Officers, 2004-2023; 2024
  - ENY/ACRL Professional Development Grants, 2015-2018
  - Librarian of the Year Award, 1994-2011
  - Library Web Pages of ENY/ACRL Member Institutions, Undated
- Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 1999-2017
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  This series contains the meeting minutes for the yearly organizational meetings.
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 1999 May 17
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 2000 May 19
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 2005 May 16
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 2006 May 15
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 2007 May 21
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 2008 May 19
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 2009 May 18
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 2010 May 24
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 2011 May 23
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 2012 May 21
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 2013 May 20
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 2014 May 19
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 2015 May 19
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 2016 May 23
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 2017 May 23
- Annual Business Meeting Packets, 2006-2024
  This series contains the annual business meeting packets as well as the list of chapter officers for the Board of Directors for one year.
  - Annual Business Meeting Brochure, 2006 May 15
  - Annual Business Meeting Brochure, 2007 May 21
  - Annual Business Meeting Brochure, 2008 May 19
  - Annual Business Meeting Brochure, 2009 May 18
  - Annual Business Meeting Brochure, 2010 May 24
  - Annual Business Meeting Brochure, 2011 May 23
  - Annual Business Meeting Brochure, 2012 May 21
  - Annual Business Meeting Brochure, 2013 May 20
  - Annual Business Meeting Brochure, 2014 May 19
  - Annual Business Meeting Brochure, 2015 May 19
  - Annual Business Meeting Brochure, 2016 May 23
  - Annual Business Meeting Brochure, 2017 May 23
  - Annual Business Meeting Brochure, 2018 May 22
  - Annual Business Meeting Brochure, 2019 May 22
  - Chapter Officers, Board of Directors, 2023-2024; 2024
- Annual Reports to ACRL, 1998-2018
  This series contains the yearly reports sent as a smaller chapter of the Association of College and Research Libraries (ACRL) to the larger national organization. Also included are strategic plans, reports reagrding the Communities of Practice Assembly (CoPA), and activity reporting.
  - ACRL Chapter 1997-98 Annual Report, 1998
  - ACRL Chapter Annual Report, 1998-1999
  - ACRL Chapter Annual Report 1999-2000
  - ACRL Chapter Annual Report 2001
  - ACRL Chapter Annual Report 2002
  - ACRL Chapter Annual Report 2004
  - ACRL Chapter Annual Report 2005
  - President's Annual Report 2005/2006
  - ACRL Strategic Plan Implementation Report Form for ACRL Units, 2009
  - ENY/ACRL's Annual Report to ACRL, 2010
  - Eastern New York Chapter 2011 ACRL SPIR
  - ACRL Annual Report 2012 Strategic Area: Value of Academic Libraries
  - FY13 ACRL CoPA Plan for Excellence Implementation Reports, 2013
  - FY14 ACRL CoPA Plan for Excellence Reports, 2014
  - FY15 ACRL CoPA Plan for Excellence Reports, 2015
  - Eastern New York Chapter Plan for Excellence Activity Reporting, 2016
  - Local Arrangements & Conference Planning Handbook, 1999-2018
- Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2005-2018
  This series contains the minutes from the Board of Directors meetings.
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2005 April 26
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2005 August 11
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2006 February 28
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2006 May 15
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2006 August 2
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2007 January 10
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2007 May 21
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2007 August 10
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2008 January 17
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2008 May 19
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2008 August 4
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2009 January 8
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2009 May 18
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2009 August 13
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2010 January 21
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2010 March 17
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2010 May 24
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2010 August 17
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2011 February 11
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2011 May 23
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2011 August 29
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2012 February 17
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2012 May 21
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2012 July 18
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2012 November 9
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2013 February 25
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2013 May 20
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2013 July 30
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2014 February 6
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2014 May 19
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2014 July 30
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2015 May 19
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2015 August 19
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2016 August 22
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2017 February 7
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2017 May 23
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2017 August 14
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2017 December 15
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2018 January 19
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2018 March 5
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2018 May 22
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2018 August 15
- Conference Programs Planning, 1975-2019
  This series contains conference programs, schedules, presentations and posters, and other conference organizational materials related to the ENY/ACRL conferences, previously hosted biannually in both the fall and spring. It began to be occur annually in only the Spring in 2006.
  - 1996 Spring Conference Information, 1996 March 8
  - 1996 ENY/ACRL Fall Conference Program, 1996 October 11
  - 1997 Spring Conference Program, 1997 March 21
  - Spring Conference 1998 Program, 1998 May 8
  - Fall Conference 1998 Program, 1998 October 26
  - Spring Conference 1999 Program, 1999 May 17
  - Fall Conference 1999 Program, 1999 October 18
  - ENY/ACRL Spring Conference 2000 Program, 2000 May 19
  - ENY/ACRL Fall Conference 2000, 2000 October 2
  - ENY/ACRL Spring Conference Program, 2001 May 21
  - 2001 Fall Conference Program, 2001 October 22
  - 2002 Fall Conference Program, 2002 October 18
  - 2002 Spring Conference Program, 2002 May 5-2002 May 6
  - 2003 Fall Conference Program, 2003 October 10
  - ENY/ACRL Spring Conference 2004 Program, 2004 May 17
  - ENY/ACRL Fall Conference 2005 Program, 2005 October 21
  - Spring Conference 2005 Program, 2005 May 15-2005 May 16
  - Spring Conference 2006 Program, 2006 May 14-2006 May 15
  - Spring Conference 2007 Program, 2007 May 20-2007 May 21
  - Spring Conference 2008 Program, 2008 May 19
  - ENY/ACRL Annual Conference Program, 2009 May 18
  - ENY/ACRL Annual Conference Program, 2010 May 24
  - ENY/ACRL Annual Conference Program, 2011 May 23
  - Spring 2012 Conference Breakout Sessions, 2012 May 21
  - Spring 2012 Conference Lightning Rounds, 2012 May 21
  - Spring 2012 Conference Poster Presentations, 2012 May 21
  - Spring 2012 Conference Program, Basic, 2012 May 21
  - Spring 2012 Conference Schedule, 2012 May 21
  - Spring 2013 Conference Program, Basic, 2013 May 20
  - Spring 2014 Conference Breakout Sessions, 2014 May 19
  - Spring 2014 Conference Lightning Round Presentations, 2014 May 19
  - Spring 2014 Conference Local Arrangements, 2014 May 19
  - Spring 2014 Conference Poster Presentations, 2014 May 19
  - Spring 2014 Conference Schedule, 2014 May 19
  - Spring 2015 Conference Local Arrangements, 2015 May 18
  - Spring 2015 Conference Breakout Sessions, 2015 May 19
  - Spring 2015 Conference Lightning Rounds, 2015 May 19
  - Spring 2015 Conferences Poster Presentations, 2015 May 19
  - Spring 2015 Conference Schedule, 2015 May 19
  - Spring 2016 Conference Local Arrangements, 2016 May 22
  - Spring 2016 Conference Lightning Rounds
  - Spring 2016 Conference Poster Sessions
  - Spring 2016 Conference Schedule
  - 2017 ENY/ACRL Spring Conference Intinerary
  - Spring 2017 Conference Lightning Round
  - Spring 2017 Conference Local Arrangements
  - Spring 2017 Conference Posters
  - Spring 2018 Conference Local Arrangements, 2018 May 22
  - Spring 2018 Conference Posters, 2018 May 22
  - Spring 2018 Conference Program, 2018 May 22
  - Spring 2019 Conference Local Arrangements, 2019 May 22
  - Spring 2019 Conference Schedule, 2019 May 22
  - Spring 2019 Conference Speakers, 2019 May 22
  - Conference Locations and Themes History, 1975-2001
- Newsletters, 1996-2021
  This series contains the digitial newsletter that was sent at least annually, but sometimes biannually in the fall and spring, and triannually in the spring, fall, and winter.
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 1996, 1996 April 9
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 1996, 1996 August 1
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Winter 1997, 1997 January 22
  - Fall 1997 ENY/ACRL Newsletter, 1997 September 10
  - Fall 1998 ENY/ACRL Newsletter, 1998 March 8; 1999
  - Spring 1998 ENY/ACRL Newsletter, 1998 April 23; 1997-1998
  - Winter 1998-99 ENY/ACRL Newsletter, 1999 March 10; 1999
  - Spring 1999 ENY/ACRL Newsletter, 1999 August 19
  - Fall 1999 ENY/ACRL Newsletter, 1999 September 21
  - Winter 2000 ENY/ACRL Newsletter, 2000 February 13
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2000, 2000 June 2
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2000, 2000 August 30
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Winter 2001, 2001 February 4
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2001, 2001 June 12
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2001, 2001 September 4; 2001 September 26
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Winter 2002, 2002 January 23
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2002, 2002 June 11
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2002, 2002 October 2
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Winter 2003, 2003 January 21
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2003, 2003 September 15
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2003
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Winter 2004, 2004 February 10
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2004, 2004 May 17
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2004, 2004 September 15
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Winter 2005, 2005 March 17
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2005, 2005 September 15
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2005
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2006, 2010 May 17
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2006, 2010 May 17
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Winter 2006, 2010 May 17
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2007
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Winter 2007
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2008
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2008
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2009
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2009
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2010
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2010
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2011
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2011
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2012
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2012
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2013
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2013
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2014
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2014
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2015
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2015
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2016
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2016
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2017
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2017
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2018
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2018
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2019
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2019
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Spring 2020
  - ENY/ACRL Newsletter, Fall 2020/Spring 2021, 2020-2021